Okay, so let's talk about the schedule
then.
So as we mentioned in one of the earlier
videos, schedule
management is a huge topic.
There's a lot of sub-lessons
in schedule management and
that's the reason why we've
broken it up into two lessons.
So lesson five is Schedule
Management Part 1 and then we have
Lesson 6, which is going to be
Schedule Management Part 2.
now the schedule itself i mean what is
schedule management about right well it's
about obviously the timeline right when do
we start the project when do we finish the
project and then what's all the different
timelines in between right what's our
major deliverables what's our major
milestones within the project when does an
activity start when does an activity
finish and so and so and so far so that's
obviously what the schedule
uh refers to right so what's
our deadline when should
we finish the project by.
Now, in scope management,
just a quick review, in scope
management, we were determining
what work needs to be done.
We were looking at the overall project,
right, and then we're creating the scope
of the project, we're
collecting some requirements,
creating the scope, creating
the work breakdown structure.
Remember, the work breakdown structure is
decomposing your project
down to the work package.
So now we know this is the work that needs
to be done.
So in scope management,
we were discussing what the
work is that needs to be
accomplished for this project.
In schedule management, we're looking at
when is that work going to be delivered.
That's the difference here.
In scope, we're talking about the what,
in schedule, we're talking about when.
When is it going to be delivered?
And there's a couple different approaches
of you know there's a few different
approaches based on whether you're
predictive or whether it's a predictive
project whether it's a agile project right
but so this whole of schedule management
then is all about planning and managing
the processes to complete the deliverable
so whereas the work breakdown structure as
part of scope management is decomposing
the project down to the work package in
schedule management we're taking each work
package further decomposing it further
breaking it down into individual
activities and these activities then that
is going to be adding value that based on
or these activities are going to be adding
value and that is what we are going to be
delivering we're going to be delivering
this value now there's many ways of
developing our schedule the methodology
that we are going to spend some time on in
subsequent videos there's something called
critical path methodology but there's many
different ways of creating your schedule
the one that you need to know for the exam
is a critical path and that's why we're
going to spend several videos actually on
critical path but again what methodology
we're going to be using we need to
determine that plus unit of measure right
so when we cannot coming up with the
schedule it's not always days weeks months
it could be FTE's full-time equivalents it
could be a level of effort
this activity requires 20
hours worth of work and
so on and so on and stuff up.
And also remember, a schedule is a major
constraint on a project.
It is a major constraint.
So remember in one of the earlier video
that we talked about the six constraints,
six major constraints, scope, schedule,
budget, resources, quality and risk.
So schedule is one of the major
constraints in a project.
You have to finish your project by a
certain deadline.
A project is never going to be,
oh, you know, finish it whenever you want
to, start it, and then, you
know, it doesn't matter
when you finish it, just
finish it whenever you want to.
That's not really a project then,
right?
A project has to have some kind of
deadline.
Now, obviously, deadlines can change,
right?
But we have to have some kind of plan,
We need to finish this project by,
you know, hopefully by this date.
And so, since we need to finish it by this
date, it is a major
constraint on the project.
So schedule management then is a very,
very important aspect, obviously,
of a project, right?
Schedule as well as cost, right?
Cost of which, you know, we're going to be
covering in subsequent videos.
But scheduling costs are the two major,
major constraints that senior management
are always looking at when it comes to,
when it comes to projects.
Now, in Agile, the
closest thing to a schedule
is something called a product roadmap.
So in the Agile world, you don't
necessarily have a true schedule as such,
you have something called a product
roadmap.
And we'll be discussing the product
roadmap in a subsequent video as well.